Women's Action Alliance Records, 1970-1996
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES II. PROJECTS 1972-96
  - Education
    - Non-Sexist Child Development Project
      - Materials developed and distributed
        - Publications
          - A Model for Non-Sexist Childhood Development: A Pre-School Program 1975 (Box 125, Folder 8)
          - Non-Sexist Education for Young Children: A Practical Guide (1975-76) (includes correspondence and reviews) (Box 125, Folder 9-10)
          - Perspectives on Non-Sexist Childhood Education (proceedings of the Conference on Non-Sexist Childhood Education, 1976): ads and reviews, consent forms, correspondence, papers (Box 125, Folder 11-16)
          - Equal Play
            - Administration: correspondence, fundraising, meeting notes, subscription letters, 1984-85, undated (Box 126-128)
            - Articles and issues, general
              - Corrections, circa 1988 (Box 128, Folder 3)
              - Articles not used, undated (Box 128, Folder 4)
              - Design correspondence and notes, 1986-88, undated (Box 128, Folder 5)
              - Illustrations: galleys, undated (Box 128, Folder 6)
              - Manuscripts, 1984, undated (Box 128, Folder 7)
              - Miscellany (Box 128, Folder 8-9)
            - Special issues: include manuscripts, correspondence, research material
              - Boys (Fall 1987): includes essays by elementary and junior high school students (Box 128-129)
              - Career Education Fall 1984 (Box 129, Folder 7)
              - Computers Spring/Fall 1983 (Box 129, Folder 8)
              - International Issue Spring 1988 (Box 129, Folder 9)
              - Sports, 1984-85 (Box 129, Folder 10-12)
              - Substance Abuse, 1988-89 (Box 129, Folder 13)
              - Teen Pregnancy Summer 1989 (Box 129-130)
            - Subjects (Box 130-133)
            - Published issues, 1980-89 (Box 133, Folder 6-7)
      - Symposia, workshops, and conferences
        - NSCD Director presentations to other organizations, Barbara Sprung and Merle Froschl: program materials, notes, correspondence, 1973-81 (Box 133-134)
        - WAA-sponsored events
          - Conference on Non-Sexist Childhood Education, Oct 1976
            - Planning (Box 135, Folder 1-11)
            - Conference
              - Airlee House (conference site) (Box 135, Folder 12)
              - Airport transportation (Box 135, Folder 13)
              - Attendance slips (Box 135, Folder 14)
              - Expenses and budget (Box 135, Folder 15)
              - Opening remarks, Ruth Abram (Box 135, Folder 16)
              - Keynote address and comments (Box 135, Folder 17)
              - Packet materials (Box 136, Folder 1-3)
              - Packing slips (Box 136, Folder 4)
              - Program and revisions (Box 136, Folder 5)
              - Workshop outlines (Box 136, Folder 6)
              - Panel materials (includes Letty Cottin Pogrebin) (Box 136, Folder 7-10)
              - Presenters
                - Biographies (Box 137, Folder 1)
                - Correspondence (Box 137, Folder 2)
                - Individual files, B-W (includes c.v.'s, correspondence, and papers delivered) (Box 137, Folder 3-39)
            - Post-conference follow-up: includes action sessions and conference report) (Box 137-138)
              [see also SERIES IV. PHOTOGRAPHS and SERIES V. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIAL]
          - Symposium on Multi-Cultural Approaches to Non-Sexist Early Childhood Development, November 1977
            - Administration (includes correspondence, registration forms, bibliographies and catalogs, participant packet, and Barbara Sprung's opening remarks) 1977 (Box 138-139)
            - Summaries and follow-up (includes papers delivered) (Box 139, Folder 4-12)
          - Conference on Families: proposals, 1978 (Box 139, Folder 13)
          - Children and Television Conference: correspondence, organization files, receipts, and invoices, 1979 (Box 139-140)
          - Institute for Equal Early Education (Loveland, OH), June 1980
            - Planning: budget, correspondence, proposals, application materials, minutes, and publicity (Box 140, Folder 3-16)
            - Conference: includes commitment statements, opening remarks, packet materials, registrations, resource files, workshop materials, and studies, including "The Status of Girls and Young Women in New York City" and "Women and Girls as Portrayed in English- Language Textbooks," and other studies on classroom sexism in New Delhi, India, 1977 (Box 141-142)
            - Follow-up: includes evaluations and notes and memoranda toward the final report (Box 142, Folder 2-4)
          - "Access to Equality Conference" (Box 142)
            see Project R.E.E.D.
      - Related programs
        - Beginning Equal: The Project on Non-Sexist Childrearing for Infants and Toddlers (BE), circa 1981-83
          - Administration: administrative and financial material; correspondence; evaluations and reports; and field research observations, interviews, and assessments (Box 142-144)
          - Beginning Equal: A Manual About Non- Sexist Development for Infants and Toddlers (1983): correspondence and memoranda, draft materials, mailing list, reprint permission, and press materials, 1983-84 (Box 144-145)
          - Workshops: calendars, formats, goal sheets, infant-toddler presentations, task cards, Spanish translations, toy workshop outline, and trainer comments and activity lists (Box 145, Folder 4-16)
        - Computer Equity Trainers Project (CETP)
          - Administration: committee materials, clippings, correspondence, evaluations, staff information, promotional material, and research, circa 1984-88 (Box 146-147)
          - Development: correspondence; reports; funder research, solicitation, and proposals, including for the Women's Educational Equity Act Program; and projects, including "Increasing Female Retention in Graduate School Computer Science," "Sally Ride Special," and "Training for Computer Equality," 1982-89 (Box 147-150)
          - Fieldwork
            - Pilot test (NJ, WI, OR): correspondence, reports, guideline, site visit schedule, 1983-85 (Box 150, Folder 1-5)
            - Field test (CA, NE, VT, TX, RI): correspondence, findings, Middle School Computer Use Administration Manual, Model of Computer Use (flow chart), strategy Memoranda, and post-test reply forms (Box 150, Folder 6-15)
            - Surveys: questionnaires and results, 1985 (Box 150, Folder 16-24)
            - Workshops: includes trainer's workshop guides: "What is Computer Equity?" and "Computer Equity in Math and Science" (Box 150, Folder 25-27)
          - Manual, Jo Sanders and Antonia Stone, The Neuter Computer: Why and How to Encourage Computer Equity for Girls: drafts, research materials, publicity, reports, and statistics, 1982-87 (Box 150-151)
          - Booklets: Jo Sanders and Mary McGinnis, "What is Computer Equity?"; "Counting on Computer Equity: A Quick and Easy Guide for Finding Out If Your School has a Computer Gap," 1991; "Do Your Female Students Say 'No Thanks' to the Computer?" (Box 151, Folder 12)
          - Math Anxiety packet, undated (Box 151, Folder 13)
        - Portable Women's History Museum Project, 1979- 86
          - Administration: abstracts, outlines, project descriptions, committee materials, budgets, correspondence, notes, memoranda (Box 151, Folder 14-21)
          - Development: funder research and proposal (Box 152, Folder 1-10)
        - Project R.E.E.D: Resources on Education Equity for the Disabled
          - Administration
            - Overviews, budgets, and contracts, 1980-81 (Box 153, Folder 1-4)
            - Correspondence and memoranda, 1980-83 (Box 153, Folder 5-18)
            - Financial materials, 1980-1983 (Box 154, Folder 1-3)
            - Job searches, 1980 (Box 154, Folder 4-6)
            - Mailing lists, 1981 (Box 154, Folder 7)
            - Miscellany and notes, undated (Box 154, Folder 8-9)
            - Planning and advisory meetings, 1980-81 (Box 154, Folder 10-11)
            - Proposals, 1980-81 (Box 154-155)
            - Publicity, 1981-82 (Box 155, Folder 2)
            - Reports, 1980-82 (Box 155, Folder 3-6)
            - Requests for Information, 1979-83 (Box 155, Folder 7)
            - Staff resumes, 1981 (Box 155, Folder 8)
          - Research and development
            - General and articles, 1977-1979 (Box 155, Folder 9-10)
            - Correspondence, 1980-1982 (Box 156, Folder 1)
            - Handicapped Rehabilitation Acts of 1973, 1980 (Box 156, Folder 2)
            - International, 1981 (Box 156, Folder 3)
            - Literature analysis: review and comment sheets, 1981 (Box 156-157)
            - Literature Search, 1980-82 (Box 157, Folder 6-8)
            - Mainstreaming: contracts and model releases; photograph subjects notes and miscellany; and requests; 1978-81 (Box 157-158)
            - No More Stares (Disability Rights Education and Defense Fund's Disabled Women's Educational Equity Project): drafts, correspondence, needs assessment, and site observations, 1980-82 (Box 158, Folder 11-19)
            - Resources, includes Bloomingdale Family Program (New York City) and Kids Projects of New York State and California, 1980-82 (Box 158, Folder 20-23)
            - Statistics, 1979 (Box 159, Folder 1)
            - Training manual Creating a New Mainstream: correspondence, drafts, and comment forms, 1981-82 (Box 159, Folder 2-7)
            - Pilot Testing, 1981
              - Educational Alliance (New York City), May 1981 (Box 159, Folder 8)
              - Forms: site listings (Box 159, Folder 9)
              - Garden City Nursery School (Box 159, Folder 10)
              - Goddard/Riverside Headstart (Box 159, Folder 11)
                - Little Red School House (New York City) (Box 159, Folder 12)
                - Passaic, New Jersey Headstart (Box 159, Folder 13)
                - United Cerebral Palsy (New York City) (Box 159, Folder 14)
            - Workshops, includes general information and participant evaluations, 1980-81 (Box 160, Folder 1-6)
            - National Field Testing: correspondence, notes, summaries, pre-test training session, resource packet, and site materials, including CA, FL, MA, NC, and OR, 1981-82 (Box 160-162)
            - "Access to Equality" Conference: includes conference materials and plans of action, 1981-82 (Box 162-164)
        - Science Readiness Proposal, 1982 (Box 164, Folder 6)
        - Project T.R.E.E: Training Resources for Educational Equity
          - Administration: brochure, correspondence, financial materials, evaluations, proposals, reports, 1978-79 (Box 164-165)
          - Maximizing Young Children's Potential: A Non-Sexist Manual for Early Childhood Trainers: drafts, evaluation forms, permissions, correspondence, galley, 1978-79 (Box 165-166)
          - Training: agendas, notes, guidelines, workshop instructions and materials (some in Spanish translations) evaluations, and follow-up, 1977-78 (Box 166, Folder 7-17)
  - Health
    - Resource Mothers Project: brochures, proposals and text to Opening Doors for Healthier Families: A Guide for Resource Mothers (1993), 1994-96, undated (Box 167, Folder 1-7)
    - Teenage Pregnancy Prevention Project (TAPP)
      - Administration: correspondence, 1986-88 (Box 167, Folder 8-9)
      - Development: correspondence, funder information, proposals, and report edited by Jo Sanders, "Teenage Pregnancy and the Schools: A Gender Equity Issue," 1985-88, undated (Box 167-168)
      - Organizations, arranged alphabetically (Box 168, Folder 5-11)
      - "A National Directory of Teenage Pregnancy Prevention Programs"
        - Directory (Box 168, Folder 12)
        - Questionnaire model (Box 168, Folder 13)
        - Late replies (Box 168, Folder 14-15)
        - Programs, organized by state (Box 168-172)
      - Project files, organized alphabetically (Box 173-178)
      - State files: includes printed material from teenage pregnancy prevention programs, organized by state (Box 178-182)
    - Women's Alcohol and Drug Education Program
      - Advisory board (includes minutes, list), 1994 (Box 183, Folder 1)
      - Alcohol and Drug Abuse: program materials, 1988, undated (Box 183, Folder 2)
      - Brochures, undated (Box 183, Folder 3)
      - Minutes and agendas, 1992 (Box 183, Folder 4)
      - Miscellany, 1992-94, undated (Box 183, Folder 5)
      - Development: correspondence, proposals, reports, 1995-96 (Box 183, Folder 6-14)
        [see also SERIES I. ADMINISTRATION-Development-Funders, A-Z]
      - Rolodex cards, Project Director Chris Kirk (Box 183, Folder 15)
      - "Women Tell Their Stories:" project report, undated (Box 184, Folder 1)
      - Workshop True/False cards, undated (Box 184, Folder 2)
      - Collaboration with Eurphrasian Residence of Good Shepherd Services: notes, reports, correspondence, site assessments, data, literature, and evaluation, 1992-93 (Box 184, Folder 3-11)
      - Collaboration with Hispanic Women's Center: progress log, notes, reports, budgets, correspondence, site assessments, data, and literature, 1992-93 (Box 184, Folder 12-19)
      - "Building A.T.O.D. Intervention Skills for Working with Women," information packet and instructional materials, undated (Box 184, Folder 20)
      - "Alcohol, Tobacco and other Drug Prevention with Adolescent Girls," Chris Kirk, 1990 (Box 184, Folder 21)
      - "Putting the Pieces Together: Effective Multicultural Strategies for Preventing Alcohol, Tobacco and Other Drug Use Among Women and Girls," conference, 1995: correspondence, mailing list, and packet materials (Box 184, Folder 22-25)
      - Paula Roth, ed., Alcohol and Drugs are Women's Issues, Vols I & II (Metuchen: Scarecrow Press, 1991) (Box 185)
      - Chris Kirk, et al, "The Multicultural Prenatal Alcohol and Drug Prevention Project: Replicating the Program Model: A Companion Guide to the Video Listen to Us." (Box 185)
  - Coalitions
    - National Women's Agenda Project
      - Administration
        - Overview, 1976 (Box 186, Folder 1)
        - Committees: correspondence, lists, and meeting materials
          - Advisory Committee on Women in Corporations, 1976 (Box 186, Folder 2)
          - Citizens Support, 1976-77 (Box 186, Folder 3)
          - Joint Working/Structure, 1977 (Box 186, Folder 4)
          - Steering, 1978-79 (Box 186, Folder 5-12)
          - Structure, 1976-77 (Box 186, Folder 13-19)
          - Working, 1975-78 (Box 186-187)
        - Correspondence: general, board, and letters to the Friends of the Alliance from Ruth Abram, 1975-78 (Box 187, Folder 17-22)
        - Finances and development
          - Financial records: budgets and ledger sheets, 1976-1979 (Box 187, Folder 23-26)
          - Financial miscellany (Box 188, Folder 1)
          - Fundraising: includes correspondence, foundation research materials, proposals, reports, and records, 1975-80 (Box 188, Folder 2-10)
        - Memoranda (in-office), 1976-1980 (Box 188, Folder 11-15)
        - Public relations consultation, correspondence and notes, 1976 (Box 189, Folder 1)
        - Staff
          - Interns: general and hiring correspondence, evaluations, and projects, 1976-80 (Box 189, Folder 2-6)
            [see also National Women's Agenda Project-Projects-Media Monitoring Project]
          - Interviewing notes and miscellany (Box 189, Folder 7)
          - Job descriptions, 1977-78, undated (Box 189, Folder 8)
          - Meetings: includes agenda staff, agenda strategy, and agenda and library meetings, 1976-77 (Box 189, Folder 9-11)
          - Re-structuring: includes general and Project SHARE, 1977-79 (Box 189, Folder 12-13)
          - Washington, D.C. staff position: correspondence and lobbying log, 1977-78 (Box 189, Folder 14-17)
          - Anne Bowen
            - Calendars (Box 190, Folder 1)
              [see OVERSIZE]
            - Correspondence: general and board 1977-80 (Box 190, Folder 2-6)
            - Memoranda (in-office), 1977-80 (Box 190, Folder 7)
            - National Women's Agenda Project Evaluation, 1980 (Box 190, Folder 8)
            - Notes, 1979-80 (Box 190, Folder 9)
            - Subject files
              - Berkshire Conference (Box 190, Folder 10)
              - Coalition of Labor Union Women (Box 190, Folder 11)
              - Girls Clubs of America (Box 190, Folder 12)
              - Miscellaneous (Box 190, Folder 13)
              - Money Show (Box 190, Folder 14)
              - National Center for Alcohol Education (Box 190, Folder 15)
              - New Directions for Young Women (Box 190, Folder 16)
              - New York Multiservice Women's Center (Box 190, Folder 17)
              - Ruth Shapiro Associates (Box 190, Folder 18)
              - United Auto Workers Progressive Alliance (Box 190, Folder 19)
              - U.S. Department of Labor, Women's Bureau (Box 191, Folder 1)
              - Willmar 8 (Box 191, Folder 2)
          - Susan Jenkins (Director of Public Affairs, Administrative Director, Task Force Coordinator), correspondence, 1975-76 (Box 191, Folder 3)
          - Madeline Lee (Director)
            - Correspondence: general and board, 1975-78 (Box 191, Folder 4-7)
            - Speech notes, undated (Box 191, Folder 8)
            - Subject files
              - Aspen Institute (Box 191, Folder 9)
              - Summer Institute of Women's History (includes correspondence from Margaret Mead) (Box 191, Folder 10)
              - Women in the Economy Conference (Box 191, Folder 11)
              - Women's Institute for Freedom of the Press (Box 191, Folder 12)
              - WorkPlace (Box 191, Folder 13)
          - Catherine Samuels, (Director): correspondence and miscellany, 1975-76 (Box 191, Folder 14-16)
        - State Coalitions: general and conference materials from California Women's Coalition, Illinois Women's Agenda, and Michigan Women's Agenda, 1976-80 (Box 191, Folder 17-21)
      - Projects
        - Platform development (U.S. National Women's Agenda)
          - Correspondence: general, to organizations, and mailing lists, 1975-76 (Box 192, Folder 1-3)
          - Endorsements (Box 192, Folder 4)
          - Events
            - Agenda Day, 2 Dec 1975: planning materials, clippings, and speeches (Box 192, Folder 5-8)
            - U.S. National Women's Agenda Conference: "Beyond Suffrage," 1-2 Oct 1976
              - Pre-conference correspondence and planning materials (includes correspondence from offices of presidential candidates) (Box 192, Folder 9-14)
              - Conference materials (includes packet, photos, speech by Jimmy Carter) 1976 (Box 192-193)
              - Post-conference correspondence and protest re: press coverage (Box 193, Folder 8-9)
          - Proposals, drafts, and notes, 1975 (Box 193, Folder 10)
          - Publicity: clippings, press releases, promotional materials, 1975-76 (Box 193, Folder 11-13)
          - Questionnaires: notes and responses filed alphabetically by organization, undated (Box 194, Folder 1-8)
        - Task Forces: correspondence, proposals, meeting materials, questionnaires, and materials relating to the drafting of "Plans of Action" on the planks of the U.S. National Women's Agenda, 1975-78 (Box 195, Folder 1-15)
        - International Women's Year
          - Correspondence: general and re: relationship of National Women's Agenda Project to International Women's Year, 1976-77 (Box 196, Folder 2-3)
          - National Women's Conference, Houston, 1977
            - Pre-conference: planning materials, state convention materials, and press releases (Box 196, Folder 4-6)
            - Conference: packet, delegate list and voting records, and Pro-plan [pro-ERA] caucus material (Box 196, Folder 7-9)
            - Post-conference: bulletins, correspondence, and reports, 1978 (Box 196, Folder 10-12)
          - Research materials: printed material, reports, and publicity, 1975-77 (Box 197, Folder 1-2)
        - National Women's Agenda Coalition
          - Administrative
            - Correspondence: general and requests for information, 1978-79 (Box 197, Folder 3-5)
            - Dues, 1978-79, undated (Box 197, Folder 6)
            - Membership applications: positive, negative, and pending (Box 197, Folder 7-11)
            - Membership certificates, 1978 (Box 197, Folder 12)
            - Membership lists and follow-up forms, 1976-79, undated (Box 197, Folder 13)
            - Membership profiles: correspondence, questionnaires, summary, and updates, 1977-79 (Box 198, Folder 1-4)
            - Publicity drafts, undated (Box 198, Folder 5-6)
            - Recruitment, 1977-79 (Box 198, Folder 7-9)
            - Structure/Planning
              - Consultation correspondence and reports, meeting materials, and worksheets, 1975-78 (Box 198, Folder 10-12)
              - Working paper drafts, notes, and responses, 1976-77 (Box 198-199)
              - Summary of Coalition Activity, 1978 (Box 199, Folder 2)
          - Projects
            - Agenda Alerts, 1978-80 (Box 199, Folder 3)
            - Agenda Alert files (organized by date) (Box 199, Folder 4-22)
            - Agenda alert resource files, 1978- 1979
              - Anti-ERA [see also IWY] (Box 200, Folder 1)
              - Communications Act (Box 200, Folder 2)
              - Constitutional Convention (Box 200, Folder 3)
              - Department of HEW Social Security Recommendations (Box 200, Folder 4)
              - Medicaid Abortion Funding (Box 200, Folder 5)
              - Office of Federal Contract Compliance Programs (Box 200, Folder 6)
              - Pregnancy Disability Bill (Box 200, Folder 7)
            - National Women's Agenda [Coalition] Conference, 9-11 Mar 1978
              - Pre-conference planning correspondence, 1975-78 (Box 200, Folder 8-11)
              - Conference packet, meeting materials, notes, participant list, workshop materials, and speeches (Box 200, Folder 12-18)
              - Post-conference follow up (Box 200, Folder 19)
            - National Women's Agenda Coalition Conference, 1-2 Dec 1978
              - Pre-conference correspondence, lists, and planning materials (Box 200, Folder 20-25)
              - Conference packet, meeting materials, and presentation materials (Box 201, Folder 1-4)
              - Post-conference correspondence, report, and protest (Box 201, Folder 5-6)
            - Introduction to the Alliance workshop, 1979 (Box 201, Folder 7)
            - Leadership Day, 30 Nov 1978 (Box 201, Folder 8-9)
            - Media Monitoring Project, 1980: internship materials, guidelines, surveys, report, and research materials (Box 201-202)
            - Resource catalog, 1978-79: catalog, drafts, and correspondence (Box 203, Folder 1-4)
            - Satellite Project
              - Correspondence, 1977-79, undated (Box 203, Folder 5)
              - Memoranda, 1977 (Box 203, Folder 6)
              - Minutes, 1977 (Box 203, Folder 7)
              - Miscellany (Box 203, Folder 8)
              - NASA conference, 1977: conference materials, correspondence, and reports (Box 203, Folder 9-11)
              - Notes (Box 203, Folder 12)
              - Proposals, general and with Emerson College, 1977 (Box 203, Folder 13-14)
              - Protest re: handling of project, 1978 (Box 203, Folder 15)
              - Questionnaire mailing and responses, 1977 (Box 204, Folder 1-2)
              - Report, 1978 (Box 204, Folder 3)
              - Research material (Box 204, Folder 4)
            - Women's Agenda
              - Administration
                - Advertising agencies, correspondence and notes, and ad solicitation, 1976-78 (Box 204, Folder 5-6)
                - Correspondence (Box 204, Folder 7-16)
                - Design/writing (Box 205, Folder 1-7)
                - Financial records, 1976-79 (Box 205, Folder 8)